Guide to the John Elsberg literary magazine collection, 1966-2007 MS2314
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
John Elsberg literary magazine collection
1966-2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Elsberg, Constance
MS2314
2 Linear Feet
This collection contains literary publications. Each folder has a list of publication titles included. These materials date from 1966-2007.
Arrangement
Arranged in alphabetical order by publication title.
Existence and Location of Originals
There are books by John Elsberg and published by Bogg press in the Special Collections book collection. Please search John Elsberg as an author.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains literary publications. Each folder has a list of publication titles included. These materials date from 1966-2007.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Constance Elsberg, 2013 February 20 (2013.003)
Separated Materials
Issues of Bogg Magazine were separated from the collection and added to the existing serial catalog entry for Bogg magazine.
Biographical / Historical
John Elsberg (1945-2012) was the author of more than a dozen books and chapbooks of poetry. He was also the editor of the seminal small press magazine Bogg. Bogg began publication in the 1960s.Bogg was founded by George Cairncross in England. Elsberg worked with him on that publication, in the 1970s Elsberg became the US (and Australian) editor and eventually Elsberg assumed sole publishing responsibilities.
Poetry -- 20th century; Literature; Poetry; Experimental poetry -- 20th century.; Elsberg, Constance; Elsberg, John
- Poetry Magazines - A, 1978-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  General
  Titles include: 10th Muse; 78 RPM; Abarth to Zil; Abbey; Always Have Ithica; Aunt Jane & Friends; Alice to Zappa; Ank to Zen
- Poetry Magazines - B, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Titles include: British Underground Magscene News; Askew to Zimmerman
- Poetry Magazines - C, 1977-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Titles include: The Chair; Colin David Webb; The Conjuror and his Dog or Feet; Contemporary Verse Two; The Credible Adventures of Nick Toczek
- Poetry Magazines - D, 1979-1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Titles include: The Deep Earth Review; Doors into and Out of Dorset
- Poetry Magazines - E, 1976-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Titles include: EBEB; Echoes from the Waste Land; Envoi; Excello & Bollard
- Poetry Magazines - F, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Titles include: Fauxpas; Folio International
- Poetry Magazines - G, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Titles include: Gazunda; Global Tapestry; Grapeshot; GTJ
- Poetry Magazines - H, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Titles include: Half Man Half Hammock Half Marlo Brandon; Hat; HYN
- Poetry Magazines - I-J, 1978-2007 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Titles include: I Am Paraguay; Iota; Joe Soap's Canoe
- Poetry Magazines - K-L, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Titles include: Kellog's; Krax; The Lantern Angel is Coming; The Littack Supplement; Ludd's Mill
- Poetry Magazines - M, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Titles include: Magic City; Mark Williams; Max Tracks; Merseyside Poetry Circuit; The Mill
- Poetry Magazines - N [1/2], 1981-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Titles include: New Departures; New Hope International; The New Gwent Review
- Poetry Magazines - N [2/2], 1978-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Titles include: New Poetry; Northern Journal; Not to be Named
- Poetry Magazines - O, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Included titles: Oil Slick; The Old Incline; Orbis; Orpheus; Owls & Swimmers
- Poetry Magazines - P [1/2], 1980-1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Included titles: Pan's Scrubbers; Paradise Circus, Paradise Square; Peeping Tom; Poetry Books; Poetry Motel
- Poetry Magazines - P [2/2], 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  Included titles: Press Pigeons; Progress of the Soul; Psychopoetica
- Poetry Magazines - R, 1977-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Included titles: Raedinga; Reviews of this Chapbook; The Romantic Abstract of the Physical Agon
- Poetry Magazines - S [1/4], 1975-1989 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  Included titles: Samisdat; Sandwiches; Savage; Scree
- Poetry Magazines - S [2/4], 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  Included titles: Scree; Self Abused but Still Standing; Sepia; Slow Dancer
- Poetry Magazines - S [3/4], 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Included titles: Small Exchange; Smoke; Sol Quarterly; Spook; Stash
- Poetry Magazines - S [4/4], 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  Included titles: Steve Sneyd; Stride; Subway Rape; Syzygy
- Poetry Magazines - T, 1971-1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Included titles: Tears in the Fence; Tides in the Sky; Tuff Stuff; Trends
- Poetry Magazines - V, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Included titles: Village Voice; Vindictment
- Poetry Magazines - W, 1976-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Included titles: Waving the Flag; Window; The Wolly of Swot; Why-Fronts
- John Elsberg loose papers for Bogg, Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)